Hello. [clears throat]
>> Um, you know, just met with the players.
Um, you know, they they've had medical,
all that stuff this morning, kind of
doing their checklist. They'll get with
the coaches and then that that's it,
man. It's hard to believe. It's, you
know, this is it. And, uh, you know,
it's going to be a hard pill to swallow
watching these teams in the playoffs.
You know, that's that's um, but I think
you got to watch them. you know, I think
you got to watch, force yourself to do
it because that's, you know, the drive
to want to be there, be a part of it,
and uh, you know, that's that's what
this business is really about, man. At
the end of the day is the competition,
finding a way to win. I thought uh the
guys earned that win yesterday, man.
They came out and collectively that team
showed up. Our team showed up and they
they fought. They played hard um and and
played complimentary football. I was
proud of them for that. questions.
>> Yeah. When a when a season ends this
way, obviously not what you wanted.
You've done a lot of winning up till
this point. Um, do you stay the course
pretty much and still stay committed to
the way you've done things or do you
look at changing making a lot of
wholesale changes, coaching, hires, you
know, personnel, whatever it might be,
scheme, anything. Do you take a whole
look at it and maybe think about tearing
it down and doing different things?
Well, I'm man, I I want to first of all,
I don't want to make any any decisions
that I'm not prepared to really think
through. So, I'm going to need a little
bit here. You know, I'm going to need a
few days um to really think about this
and and uh you know, deep dive some
areas um and
you know, I'm willing to do whatever it
t whatever is best for this team. I'm
going to do what I believe is best for
this team, I will do. Um, you know, I
think as far as doing things, some of it
is a little bit like, you know what, I I
want to get back to some of the things
we were doing a couple years ago, you
know, and what I'd say and what I mean
by that is um just getting back to a
little bit of
um what we did at the ground level, man.
Just a little bit of the way we train,
the way we go about things. Um, you
know, it's going to be a good training
camp for us. We're going to go back and
and really sharpen the sword a little
bit just, you know, and I know that's a
while a ways off, but uh I think that's
the big thing
>> from there, Dan, that you're sort of
referring to that maybe cost you.
>> I don't want to I don't want to go into
that right now. I don't want to go into
that. Dan, I know you said you want to
pick things through, but just surface
level, do you think it's more than just
tweaks that are needed with the roster
or is it tweaking?
>> I think it's I think it's a number of
things. I do. I think it's um and I
don't think um it I don't think
um
in itself one thing is not a huge thing
but I think you know when you when you
start adding up a number of things maybe
we need to do um we need to make a
couple of changes to move a couple of
guys in areas whether it's whether it's
coaches or um players. I think it's all
of that. I I think it's, you know, I
think some things that that happen are
also, man, we we learn on the fly here a
little bit too, man. Learning to adjust
as we go through and growing. Uh, which
I did think we grew as this season went
on in some areas. Um, learning to adapt,
adjust, all that. Um, you know, and
there again, we we always know we're
going to get hit by injuries, right?
That's happened every year. That's and
that's part of the NFL. Everybody gets
it. But, you know, we just always got to
think about, man, contingency plan. How
do we, you know, how do we make the most
of this roster and and really preparing
the next guy up to be ready? Um, you
know, to to step up for us for, if
possible, you know, half a season. I
mean, that that's what we that's what
we're charged with.
>> Been so much of a upward trajectory like
since you got here, every year has
gotten better and better and better.
this the first year kind of regressed in
a sense, but how much do you guys still
believe in your process as far as the
core fundamental players and do you
still believe in what you guys built?
>> Oh, for sure. For sure. We're not going
to back down on that. Um, you know, uh,
we believe in what we do. Uh, it's got
us to to where we've gotten to at this
point now. We fell short this year and
and look, we all acknowledge that. I I
acknowledge that it's it's bitter, you
know, it's a bitter taste. I mean, it
feels good to win yesterday, but
ultimately it's it's u it's frustrating,
you know. Um but we got nobody to blame
but ourselves. Um but I really don't
believe we're that far off. Uh there's a
couple of things we can do and and uh
you know, I just want to make sure, man,
we we go after it, man. We we and I'm
not saying we weren't hungry, but let's
get that hunger back. And you know,
we're going to bring in some guys to
compete. You know, that's the thing,
man. We we need we need competition in a
lot of areas, man, because that brings
out the best in players, whether it's
with some of the guys that we're here or
the guys that we bring in. That's how
you elevate the roster.
>> For uh over half the season, um I know
you prefer not to you called plays for
over half the season. I know you prefer
to not do that so you can pay attention
to some of the bigger picture stuff in
game, but
>> is are you intrigued at all by the
potential stability that being the
permanent play caller could provide? And
is that something you'll seriously
consider this off season?
>> Uh I mean I'm open to anything. I I
don't know exactly where I'm at with
that yet. I mean one of the I guess one
of the good things if I did do that you
don't have to worry about somebody else
leaving. You know you don't have to
worry about your play caller leaving. Um
so that would be one of the perks of it.
But but I'm listen I'm going to think
through all of that and and there again
I I think I really want to do what I
feel is best for the team and and that
included you know if if I believe that's
what's best for us and
you know we we and I feel good about it
then I will if if I just feel like I
don't then then I I won't do it you know
I won't do it
>> five years here you win the last regular
season game all five Yeah, a lot of
people say there's no care because it's
a different team next year. Do you feel
there's a car for winning the last game,
even though you probably could have got
better draft choices by losing the game?
>> Uh, well, yeah, I'm not worried about
the the draft, whatever. I I think it's
important if man, we play to win. You
know, we play to win. Otherwise, why why
we shouldn't have rolled out golf or St.
Brown or Reer or Decker or any of those
guys if we weren't saying we wanted to
win? You know, we we play here to win.
We got a lot of young guys on this
roster. They need to see how it's done.
They need to understand we're here to
win. We're here to compete. We're here
to get better. You know, you're not here
to just be here and get by, you know. We
we need it from everybody. And uh so I
think what's important is that we win,
you know, and we're always trying to
win. And uh no, it didn't get us
anywhere. Um but we won and that was the
objective. injuries.
>> Go ahead.
>> With Decker kind of openly contemplating
his playing future, what lessons can be
learned about the Frank Ragnoff
situation last year? Do you kind of have
to plan like you might not be here? Like
does that change the offseason plan at
all?
>> Well, you know, we're going to have to
obviously take note of that. And I know
Decker's going to come talk to Brad and
myself here, you know, either today or
tomorrow. And uh you know and and I know
this whatever goes down there you know
from his perspective he's going to need
some time. I mean you just do you know
when you've played as long as he has and
had the career he's had and you're going
to need a little bit but absolutely we
learn lessons. We we you learn lessons
there.
>> Injuries are you most proud of?
>> I'm coming back to you.
>> You most proud of from the season and
what is most disappointing?
>> Well I'm I'm proud of the way these guys
just responded every week man. It's not
easy that, you know, you win, you lose,
you win, you lose, you win, you know,
you know, and and for these guys to, of
course, it it can get frustrating, but
man, they came back to work every
Wednesday and they went after it. They
tried to improve. Uh, you know, you go
out to the games, man, they bust their
ass, and it just sometimes it doesn't
work the way you wanted it to. And, uh,
but this group, man, they never laid
down. They just came back in. They were
great teammates, you know. Um, and so I
appreciate that, man. work ethic that
these guys had. You know, obviously the
most disappointing thing is is, you
know, I said this to them yesterday. I
said it last night. We were one play
away from getting in. Basically, one
play either Minnesota game or Pittsburgh
or to you're you're probably in. You
know, you have a good chance. And so
it's that's how close it is. You know,
that's but that's that's what this
league is.
>> Injuries, Dan. um you said you've been
hit every year and obviously it's part
of the game, but um maybe a little bit
more heavier than most teams the last
two seasons. When you evaluate that on a
big picture, you know, how do you
compartmentalize
the the different components? What do
what do you need to look at there or do
you just chalk it up to a stretch of bad
luck?
>> Yeah, I think when you start talking
about some of these, it's like, man,
look at the soft tissue. That's where I
always start because if you got a major
soft tissue issue, then there's it's
more than just the player in my opinion.
There there's other factors. We've been
great. I mean, we we do a great job of
preparing our players. When you start
talking about, you know, it's an
Achilles, it's a man, those are
unfortunately those are freak things,
man. Um and so it's for whatever reason
we've just we've kind of been hit, man.
And uh you know we we've and listen as
far as practice I've done everything
man. I've I've done from walkthroughs to
we go to doing a little bit of both. And
so at the end of the day I know this.
You got to get your team prepared to
play. And and so that's what I'm always
going to hang my hat on. Um I like our
training staff. I think they do a hell
of a job. I really do. And you know it's
just it was a tough year in some areas.
>> Yep. You've been on the job now five
years. I know you'll do a comprehensive
self scout of yourself and everything,
but just if I ask, how do you feel like
you did this year on the job being the
head coach of the Lions?
>> Not good enough. We didn't get in. I
mean, we we underachieve. So, not good.
I would give myself a freaking F.
>> Of all those things you want to deep
dive this off season, you know, what's
top of the list, play calling or a
personnel thing or what? What do you
need to figure out first? I guess
>> the first thing I got to figure out is a
staff. I need to make sure that, you
know, um, you know, where do we go from
here? You know, I just need to either I
need to uh, you know, make sure that I
feel good about uh, you know, where the
guys are at, the positions they're in,
or do we tweak a couple of things, move
a couple of guys? Do we, you know, do we
stay pat? Do we th those are the things
I got to sort through. That That's the
first for me. That's what I got to get
through. And uh just you know I got I
got to do I got to do some digging here.
>> Have you made any decisions on that yet
or that's my time?
>> No, I haven't.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Heat. Hey, Heat. [music]